<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Walking on R, it&#39;s OK I guess</title>
    <link>/tags/walking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Walking on R, it&#39;s OK I guess</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/walking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Heritage walk in Kensington Market</title>
      <link>/2017/06/10/heritage-walk-in-kensington-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/10/heritage-walk-in-kensington-market/</guid>
      <description>This morning’s Heritage Walk was in Kensington Market. I grabbed a few photos.
This is the Church of St Stephen-in-the-Fields, on College between Spadina and Bathurst:
Though it is now thoroughly of downtown, when it was built (1857), it was literally in the fields. However, its mission is still the same as it was, to help new immigrants and those of the area that need help. This was a theme of the walk: the various waves of immigrants who settled the area built institutions to help their fellows out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday walk - Riverdale park(s)</title>
      <link>/2017/05/14/sunday-walk---riverdale-parks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/14/sunday-walk---riverdale-parks/</guid>
      <description>Today’s walk comes in two parts, with a pause for lunch between. Part 1:
 From Broadview station, across past the Pizza Pizza, and (carefully) across the entrance ramp to the DVP, and then down the “secret” path:
 crossing the entrance ramp on a rather dilapidated-looking bridge:
 I am never quite sure about the next bit. Today, there was a tent hidden in the trees, as if someone was living back there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fluffy yellow things</title>
      <link>/goslings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/goslings/</guid>
      <description>Seen on today’s walk around campus:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fluffy yellow things</title>
      <link>/2017/05/08/fluffy-yellow-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/08/fluffy-yellow-things/</guid>
      <description>Seen on today’s walk around campus:
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A very short walk</title>
      <link>/2017/05/05/a-very-short-walk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/05/a-very-short-walk/</guid>
      <description>An even shorter walk around campus today than yesterday; you will see why from the pictures.
The walk around the back of the residences was still passable this afternoon. Here is the substation and dilapidated truck mentioned elsewhere:
 I wondered what this was in the woods, until I remembered that this is a university and there are usually unusual art projects in unusual places. This was just around the corner from the substation:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>