<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Ken&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Ken&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Welch analysis of variance</title>
      <link>/2017/05/19/welch-analysis-of-variance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/19/welch-analysis-of-variance/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The standard analysis of variance based on the \(F\)-test has two major assumptions:
Normally distributed data Equal variance within each group.  The analysis can handle a certain amount of non-normality, but the equal-variance assumption is important because it is required for the idea of “an” error variance to make sense (that is what the error mean square is estimating).
Is it possible to make an ANOVA that can allow for the groups to have different variances?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making scatterplots against multiple explanatory variables</title>
      <link>/2017/05/16/making-scatterplots-against-multiple-explanatory-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/16/making-scatterplots-against-multiple-explanatory-variables/</guid>
      <description>Introduction An R post here.
I wanted to share something about drawing scatterplots against many variables at once, using gather, ggplot and facet_wrap from the tidyverse.
First we need to load the tidyverse:
library(tidyverse) ## Loading tidyverse: ggplot2 ## Loading tidyverse: tibble ## Loading tidyverse: tidyr ## Loading tidyverse: readr ## Loading tidyverse: purrr ## Loading tidyverse: dplyr ## Conflicts with tidy packages ---------------------------------------------- ## filter(): dplyr, stats ## lag(): dplyr, stats  Gather Let’s start with gather.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday walk - Riverdale park(s)</title>
      <link>/2017/05/14/sunday-walk---riverdale-parks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/14/sunday-walk---riverdale-parks/</guid>
      <description>Today’s walk comes in two parts, with a pause for lunch between. Part 1:
 From Broadview station, across past the Pizza Pizza, and (carefully) across the entrance ramp to the DVP, and then down the “secret” path:
 crossing the entrance ramp on a rather dilapidated-looking bridge:
 I am never quite sure about the next bit. Today, there was a tent hidden in the trees, as if someone was living back there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fluffy yellow things</title>
      <link>/2017/05/08/fluffy-yellow-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/08/fluffy-yellow-things/</guid>
      <description>Seen on today’s walk around campus:
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bike Ride</title>
      <link>/2017/05/07/bike-ride/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/07/bike-ride/</guid>
      <description>It was finally good enough weather for a bike ride today:
 Not a very long ride, but enough to get the legs going again (with some huffing and puffing into the wind).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rugby League</title>
      <link>/2017/05/07/rugby-league/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/07/rugby-league/</guid>
      <description>Last night, Megan and I went to the first ever home game of the Toronto Wolfpack. We got there early and grabbed seats about seven rows up from the field (general admission), so we were close enough to be near the action and yet high enough to get a sense of the flow of the game.
The opposition were a mid-table Oxford side, and as I said to Megan before the game, it’s not whether the Wolfpack would win, but by how many (the answer in the end was 62-12).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A very short walk</title>
      <link>/2017/05/05/a-very-short-walk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/05/a-very-short-walk/</guid>
      <description>An even shorter walk around campus today than yesterday; you will see why from the pictures.
The walk around the back of the residences was still passable this afternoon. Here is the substation and dilapidated truck mentioned elsewhere:
 I wondered what this was in the woods, until I remembered that this is a university and there are usually unusual art projects in unusual places. This was just around the corner from the substation:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Images</title>
      <link>/2017/05/03/images/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/03/images/</guid>
      <description>For my last post, I had a lot of trouble finding out how to make the images appear. It turns out that the secret is to save them in the static folder, and then to treat that folder as the “root” (that is, start its name with a forward slash) when making the R Markdown for the image. Here is a picture I took at a spot surprisingly close to where I live, in November last year:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Round the back of the S wing</title>
      <link>/2017/05/03/round-the-back-of-the-s-wing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/03/round-the-back-of-the-s-wing/</guid>
      <description>A short walk today around the back of the S wing at UTSC.
This is the side of the S wing that nobody sees; it has the concrete brutalism of the outside wall (no entrances from this side) up against the forest that leads down to Highland Creek. You don’t meet too many people around here. The path is actually perfectly passable, though there is one low spot that gets muddy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About this blog</title>
      <link>/2017/04/30/about-this-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/30/about-this-blog/</guid>
      <description>I discovered that one can host a blog on Github, on which I already have an account, via a thing called Github Pages. As if that weren’t enough, posting content to this blog is done via R Studio. I created a new project called blog that is linked to a Github repository, and installed the blogdown package (by the amazingly prolific Yihui Xie), and then I create a new post such as this one by, at the console, typing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday walk in Scarborough</title>
      <link>/2017/04/30/sunday-walk-in-scarborough/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/30/sunday-walk-in-scarborough/</guid>
      <description>Actually, a bit more than that, since I started at Kennedy station. (But I was on the phone helping my daughter with her homework when I started, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t check the GPS.)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturday walk in the city</title>
      <link>/2017/04/29/saturday-walk-in-the-city/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/29/saturday-walk-in-the-city/</guid>
      <description>So I was at Yorkdale, with no subway south. So I figured I’d arrange a walk and see how far I got. I rode the shuttle bus to Lawrence West, seeing at first hand how ill-suited Toronto is to the car: onto the Allen, a long lineup to turn left onto Lawrence (for us, to get in front of the subway station) and a zoo of cars on Lawrence, including a line of cars waiting to turn left onto the northbound Allen and blocking one of the eastbound through lanes in the process.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>