<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Ken&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Ken&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Round the back of the S wing</title>
      <link>/2017/05/03/round-the-back-of-the-s-wing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/03/round-the-back-of-the-s-wing/</guid>
      <description>A short walk today around the back of the S wing at UTSC.
 This is the side of the S wing that nobody sees; it has the concrete brutalism of the outside wall (no entrances from this side) up against the forest that leads down to Highland Creek. You don’t meet too many people around here. The back actually starts from Ellesmere Road and goes round via a substation and the back of the residences (through the trees) and comes out at the end of the SY building, from which you can go around the familiar inside of the S-wing (indoors or outdoors) or the unfamiliar outside.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About this blog</title>
      <link>/2017/04/30/about-this-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/30/about-this-blog/</guid>
      <description>I discovered that one can host a blog on Github, on which I already have an account, via a thing called Github Pages. As if that weren’t enough, posting content to this blog is done via R Studio. I created a new project called blog that is linked to a Github repository, and installed the blogdown package (by the amazingly prolific Yihui Xie), and then I create a new post such as this one by, at the console, typing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday walk in Scarborough</title>
      <link>/2017/04/30/sunday-walk-in-scarborough/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/30/sunday-walk-in-scarborough/</guid>
      <description>Actually, a bit more than that, since I started at Kennedy station. (But I was on the phone helping my daughter with her homework when I started, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t check the GPS.)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturday walk in the city</title>
      <link>/2017/04/29/saturday-walk-in-the-city/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/29/saturday-walk-in-the-city/</guid>
      <description>So I was at Yorkdale, with no subway south. So I figured I’d arrange a walk and see how far I got. I rode the shuttle bus to Lawrence West, seeing at first hand how ill-suited Toronto is to the car: onto the Allen, a long lineup to turn left onto Lawrence (for us, to get in front of the subway station) and a zoo of cars on Lawrence, including a line of cars waiting to turn left onto the northbound Allen and blocking one of the eastbound through lanes in the process.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>