<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bayesian on R, it&#39;s OK I guess</title>
    <link>/categories/bayesian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bayesian on R, it&#39;s OK I guess</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/bayesian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rating rugby league with Stan</title>
      <link>/2018/05/01/rating-rugby-league-with-stan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/01/rating-rugby-league-with-stan/</guid>
      <description>Abstract of techniques used here
 Introduction Rugby league is one of the “football” family of sports, in which players gain ground by carrying and passing and kicking the ball (like rugby union, North American football and somewhat like Australian and Gaelic football). The aim of the game is to touch the ball down behind the opponents’ goal line (a “try”, four points) after which a kick is taken at goal (a “conversion”, two points).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working my way back to you, a re-investigation of rstan</title>
      <link>/2018/02/28/working-my-way-back-to-you-a-re-investigation-of-rstan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/28/working-my-way-back-to-you-a-re-investigation-of-rstan/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I learned Stan a while back, when I was fitting some Bayesian models. I wanted to fix up one of them, and I realized that I had forgotten most of what I knew about Stan, so I had to go back and learn it again.
A Bayesian model has two parts: a prior distribution, which summarizes your belief about the parameters you are trying to estimate before you look at any data, and a model that asserts the data-generating mechanism conditional on the parameter value(s).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>