<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A Hugo website</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on A Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About this blog</title>
      <link>/2017/04/30/about-this-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/30/about-this-blog/</guid>
      <description>I discovered that one can host a blog on Github, on which I already have an account, via a thing called Github Pages. As if that weren’t enough, posting content to this blog is done via R Studio. I created a new project called blog that is linked to a Github repository, and installed the blogdown package (by the amazingly prolific Yihui Xie), and then I create a new post such as this one by, at the console, typing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday walk</title>
      <link>/2017/04/30/sunday-walk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/30/sunday-walk/</guid>
      <description>Actually, a bit more than that, since I started at Kennedy station. (But I was on the phone helping my daughter with her homework when I started, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t check the GPS.)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A post</title>
      <link>/2017/04/29/a-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/29/a-post/</guid>
      <description>nothing much here except some R:
z=1:5 z ## [1] 1 2 3 4 5 sd(z) ## [1] 1.581139 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturday walk in the city</title>
      <link>/2017/04/29/saturday-walk-in-the-city/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/29/saturday-walk-in-the-city/</guid>
      <description>So I was at Yorkdale, with no subway south. So I figured I’d arrange a walk and see how far I got. I rode the shuttle bus to Lawrence West, seeing at first hand how ill-suited Toronto is to the car: onto the Allen, a long lineup to turn left onto Lawrence (for us, to get in front of the subway station) and a zoo of cars on Lawrence, including a line of cars waiting to turn left onto the northbound Allen and blocking one of the eastbound through lanes in the process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Ken Butler is a Lecturer in Statistics at the University of Toronto Scarborough, and Supervisor of Studies of the Applied Statistics Minor program there. He also likes exploring and learning about Toronto. Hello.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>